Hozefa Tankiwala

(682) 408-1311 hozefa.tankiwala@mavs.uta.edu |www.linkedin.com/in/hozefatankiwala

Full-Stack Software developer offering experience in the full software development lifecycle - from concept through delivery of applications and customizable solutions. Acquainted with agile development practices such as Scrum, Kanban and XP by the means of industrial experience. Excellent coding and debugging skills

Technical Skills

- Programming: Python, JAVA, JavaScript, Android SDK, C, C++, Bash, MATLAB
- Database Technologies: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, SQLAlchemy,
- Web Technologies: HTML5/CSS3, ReactJS, AngularJS, VueJS, NodeJS, Serverless
- Tools: AWS Services, VS Code, Git, Google Firebase, Android Studio

Academic Projects

https://amzhtw.web.app (E-Commerce Website – Amazon Clone)

- Full-Stack and functioning E-commerce website hosted using firebase hosting and cloud functions.
- Front-end developed using ReactJS, HTML5 and CSS while Back-End is developed using Node.JS
- User Login and Registration handled using Firebase Auth.
- Accepts credit card payments through React's Stripe.js library

Experience

MA Technologies LLC.

Dallas, TX

October 2021 - Present

- **Software Developer**
 - Developed backend APIs for client consumption using Node.JS and Serverless
 - Deployed the APIs using AWS CodeBuild and AWS Lambda
 - Worked on development and maintenance of web-application for Avanta Risk Management System

Mactores Inc. Mumbai, India May 2021 - Aug 2021

Full-Stack Developer Intern

- Developed a will-writing web-application for Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance Company using ReactJS
- Deployed and hosted the application on AWS S3
- Learned AWS services in the internship training program

University of Texas at Arlington

SI Leader

Jan 2021 - Oct 2021

- Leading group learning sessions for Intermediate Programming class, promoting growth mindset.
- Design creative session plans based on important material to conduct weekly study sessions
- Serve as peer role models, by having solid leadership, note taking, communication and study skills.

Advanced Tutor Aug 2019 - Oct 2021

- Working with the University's Tutorial and Supplemental instructions program (UTSI).
- College Reading and Learning Association (CRLA) Certified Level II Tutor.
- Working with students one-on-one to help understand difficult topics.
- Tutoring wide range of subjects including sophomore level computer science classes.

Education

University of Texas at Arlington, Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, GPA: 3.95

Spring 2022

Coursework:

Algorithms and Data Structures Database Systems and File Structures

Fundamentals of Software Engineering **Programming Languages**

Academic Achievements

- Engineering Student Senator Spring 2020 Fall 2020
- Fall 2019, Spring 2020, Fall 2020, Spring 2021 Dean's list
- Maverick Academic Scholarship